<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AEF</string>

    <string name="latter_a">A</string>
    <string name="latter_e">E</string>
    <string name="latter_f">F</string>

    <string name="item_home">Home</string>
    <string name="item_about_us">About us</string>
    <string name="item_news">News</string>
    <string name="item_calendar_of_activities">Calendar of Activities</string>
    <string name="item_projects">Projects</string>
    <string name="item_contact_us">Contact us</string>


    <!--big text-->
    <string name="aef_sarf_press_release_text">
        <b>Contact Information:\n</b>
		Armenian Educational Foundation\n 
		600 West Broadway, Suite 130\n 
		Glendale, California 91204\n 
		Telephone: (818) 242-4154\n 
		Email: aef@aefweb.org\n 
		Website: www.aefweb.org\n 
		\n\n 
		FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE\n 
		Armenian Educational Foundation\n 
		PRESS RELEASE\n 
		February 8, 2016\n 
		\n\n 
		AEF Announces $65,000 Donation to Syrian Armenian Relief Fund &amp;\n 
		Scholarships to Syrian-Armenian refugee students\n 
		\n\n 
		Glendale, California.  At its 65th Anniversary Gala, the Armenian Educational  
		Foundation (AEF) announced plans to donate $25,000 to the Syrian Armenian Relief  
		Fund’s telethon on February 21st, specifically to support the struggling Armenian  
		schools in Aleppo, and $40,000 for scholarships to Syrian refugee students in  
		Armenia.  
		\n\n 
		Before the Syrian Civil War in 2011 there were 30 Armenian schools in Syria, with  
		approximately 20,000 students.  Since the onset of the war, most of the Armenian  
		schools have been destroyed and thousands of Armenian students have been  
		displaced from their homes.   
		\n\n 
		Historically, Aleppo was a hub for Syrian‐Armenians and boasted the largest  
		Armenian community in Syria with18 of the 30 Armenian schools located there.   
		Now, there are only 14 functioning Armenian schools in Syria of which only 9 are  
		left in Aleppo.  Schools were forced to consolidate and switch to a different teaching  
		system— scheduling classes in multiple shifts to accommodate students from  
		destroyed schools.   
		\n\n 
		AEF understands the necessity of helping Armenian students in Syria, and aims,  
		with the $25,000 donation, to improve the fractured education system of the  
		country and to reintroduce normalcy into the lives of the students.   
		Moreover, there are currently approximately five thousand Syrian‐Armenian  
		refugee students living in Armenia and Artsakh.  AEF plans to allocate $40,000  
		($10,000 per year for 4 years) from its Scholarship Program to fund 10 Syrian‐ 
		Armenian refugee students who attend a 4‐year public university in Armenia or  
		Artsakh.   
		\n\n 
		For more information or to make a donation, please contact the AEF office at (818)  
		242‐4154 or email aef@aefweb.org.;
		\n
    </string>

	<string name="news_first_graduating_artsakh_text">
		In May 2013 the Armenian Educational Foundation announced $100,000 funding towards establishing a four-year Computer Information Systems (CIS) degree program, in Artsakh State University (the University), in Stepanakert and signed an agreement with the University in the same year. The funding was to help finance computer hardware, software, instructor salaries, and student scholarships and start a four-year Computer Information Systems degree program with the aim of promoting IT, modern technology and employment and empowerment in Artsakh.\n 
		\n 
		AEF recognized the importance of economic development for Artsakh and believed that this project will have a big impact in developing the infrastructure needed to bring information technology companies to Artsakh.\n 
		\n 
		“A lot of work went into establishing the department, finalizing the courses, taking books to Artsakh, hiring professors, coordinating with the university leadership, but I am proud to report that the department is established in the University, and more and more students each year apply to get into this program” said Alec Baghdasaryan, AEF Board member who heads this program.\n 
		\n 
		Every year, AEF representatives have met with the University representatives and students registered in the new CIS program and received updates on the progress of the program. The first class admitted to the program was comprised of 23 students. The program that started with total financial support from AEF has grown and currently interest in the CIS program has increased to the level that the program has the second highest number of applicants at the University, and enjoys the total and financial support of the University. As of spring 2016, in total 87 students were registered in first through fourth year programs, including those who had to take a sabbatical from their studies to serve in the army.\n 
		\n 
		“This is a very proud moment for AEF and everyone that contributed to the success of the AEF’s CIS degree program at Artsakh State University” said Vahe Hacopian, President of AEF. “The graduating class has fulfilled the AEF goal of helping Artsakh State University establish a new high technology program and prepare students for the much needed IT industry rapidly growing in Artsakh. We are hopeful this program will endure and continue to grow because this program is, as the American saying goes, “a gift that will keep-on giving” to the people of Artsakh.\n 
		\n 
		In July 2016, AEF Yerevan office Executive Director, Armine Haroyan, participated in the ceremony of awarding diplomas to the first graduating class of CIS degree from Artsakh State University, making AEF Board and members dream become a reality of seeing the first students accepted in the CIS degree program, graduate and contribute toward making Artsakh a technology hub.\n 
		\n 
		AEF intends to continue supporting the CIS program at the University through its full-tuition four-year scholarship program for all qualified students. International companies have offices in Artsakh and ready to offer employment to students of the CIS program and currently a number of students are employed at international companies with offices in Artsakh. It is anticipated that all students will receive full time employment upon graduation. The high demand for IT graduates has caused increase in number of applicants and the university administration is expecting higher number of applicants and growth in this program in the future.\n 
		\n 
		Find First Graduating Class of CIS Degree Program photos here;
	</string>

	<string name="armenian_educational_foundation_text">
		Since 1950, the Armenian Educational Foundation, Inc. (AEF) has been a cornerstone of the Armenian educational movement around the world. It has lent a helping hand to hundreds of students and to dozens of schools in numerous nations. Through its many years of giving, it has proven to be one of the most enduring and productive organizations in the Diaspora.\n
		\n
		The AEF’s fundamental aim has always been the advancement of the Armenian heritage through the support of education. Its great successes have earned the organization widespread respect, recognition and appreciation.\n
		\n
		Over the past half-century, the AEF has grown into a thriving organization with a diverse membership of dedicated individuals. The AEF welcomes to its fold anyone who shares the commitment of its founding members and who will bring to the organization new energy and fresh ideas.\n
		\n
		As it looks with optimism toward the future, the AEF hopes to be of even greater assistance to young Armenians pursuing higher education, as well as to continue providing financial help to institutions in Armenia, the United States and around the world.;
	</string>
</resources>
